good morning welcome to meditating with
shaumbra Vicky I'm a cognitive
psychologist and a cognitive scientist
at the University of Toronto where I
teach and scientifically study topics
like mindfulness and related topics such
as Insight flow mystical experience
transformative experience its
consciousness
the cultivation of wisdom the aspiration
towards might have also been practicing
the constant meditation that a
contemplation by Chi Chuan
and she come over 29 years and teaching
him professionally for almost 20 years
welcome this is a progressive course we
drank for the first time you're welcome
to stay but go to look go to links in
the description to previous lessons so
every other Monday there's a Dharma day
in which I teach a practice or principle
that builds on previous practices and
principles and then Tuesday through
Friday we meet and sit together at the
end of every day Monday through Friday
there's always human a please keep your
questions for these QA days specifically
to the set of practices on teaching in
this course for more general questions
you can you're welcome to join my
livestream Q&A that's much more general
and broad it takes place every third
Friday of the month we just did our
previous Friday it was very well went
very well and every third Friday of the
month at 3 p.m. Eastern Time
please 'like this video stream when you
get a chance as it raises its building
visibility in the YouTube YouTube
algorithm and that helps me get this
course out to as many people as possible
in these challenging times so I think
that's all just to remind you that
starting next Friday we're together we
will be which will put three works of
the 25th I believe stays the 19th yes so
starting on the 25th and thereafter
every other Monday I'll be teaching an
advanced technique we're slowing the
pace down so that people who are just
joining have a chance to go back and do
the course catch up and those you've
done the course have time to practice
and deepen and internalize what you've
been taught so far and review it in
order to ask you potential questions
alright so that's it for the
announcements for today I hope you all
enjoyed a long weekend those of you who
are
a Canadian and let's get ready to
practice so we will begin when I say
begin set your phone's I do not disturb
that should be basic posture ready begin
[Music]
slowly began to come out of your
practice trying as best she can to
integrate with you cultivated in your
practice with your everyday
consciousness and cognition
perhaps by reciting the five promises to
yourself
so just reminder on Tuesdays and
Thursdays we have a very tight time for
ending and for because of a marsh edible
in my shadow we have quite a bit more
time on Mondays and Wednesdays and a
little bit more time on Fridays so today
we'll just deal probably with one
question or two one that have is from
Kirk roller I noticed that I'm still
struggling to feel as I'm getting a full
breath with belly breathing without
raising my shoulders this might be too
much information but I think this might
be a result of wearing a bra for 30
years often ones that are very tight for
aesthetics would it be good just to
spend some time practicing breathing
spreading my lungs yes so I think this
is a very prevalent problem actually for
a lot of women and so the thing to do is
to don't try to force your breath try to
see instead if you can relax into
deepest deepest breath that is naturally
occurring and you may not get your
breath very far down into your belly and
you may need to raid your shoulder now
see if what you can do is relax and open
your shoulders and let that shoulder
maybe as so as you know subtle and as
supple as possible and then again don't
try to free to to force it the fuming
they can maybe not getting enough breath
see if you can relax more and feel more
that you're open inside that there's no
restrictions inside your chest rather
than just lifting see if you can do that
sort of opening and melting and trying
as much as you can to let a natural kind
of breathing slowly erode to the tension
and slowly afford a sense that you
actually are getting complete enough
breath and see if you can work with this
over time until you then the motion that
you're allowing in your shoulders is
very subtle and you're getting a sense
that there's an inner opening around
your lungs
and that it's beginning very gradually
of its own accord to deepen into optimum
you might also want to do some exercises
that are chest opening exercises there's
various form to stretch that can help
you do that
so it's good to be back with you guys
it's good to be practicing in Sangha
again reminder next Monday I will start
teaching you some more advanced
techniques so we'll go back to Dharma
days on alternative Mondays I want to
thank you for your time and attention
for joining I want to thank my friend
techno mage Marc my beloved son Jason
please subscribe to this channel to be
notified at the next video will also
find on my channel awaking from the
meaning crisis which is Alexa Alexa
Alexia series and voices with verve a
key which is the dialogic series of
discussion series both of them explore
many of the themes many of the
principles many of the ideas that we are
making use of in the course but explore
them in more depth more integrated
fashion and set winnette within a more
comprehensive framework of the
cultivation of wisdom and the deep
response to the meaning crisis a deep
kind of resiliency and discernment
please invite others who might benefit
from this series to join you guys are
doing a great job helping me promote
this to help as many people as possible
there in the description of this video
there is a link to the discord server
that's been set up some of you know
pleasure of doubt right here in the
Sangha he there's there's people on the
discord server that are meeting and
doing the meditation and also discussing
it and also discussing all of that work
that I've been referring to at large so
that's a great place to go and fit your
this meditation and contemplation Sangha
into a wider community that and in which
some people are doing the practice but
also trying to cultivate wisdom in a
more comprehensive sense we're doing
this every day weekday morning 9:30
Eastern Time please remember continuity
practice more important than quantity
there is no enemy worse than your own
mind and body
there is no friend no true ally greater
than your own mind and body take care
everyone I'll see you tomorrow